<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Project Digitalization]]></title><description><![CDATA[Obsidian digital garden]]></description><link>http://github.com/dylang/node-rss</link><image><url>lib\media\favicon.png</url><title>Project Digitalization</title><link></link></image><generator>Webpage HTML Export plugin for Obsidian</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 09:17:33 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="lib\rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 09:17:28 GMT</pubDate><ttl>60</ttl><dc:creator></dc:creator><item><title><![CDATA[Game Design Document]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Project Digitalization is a hybrid of an action and turn-based role-playing game set in a post-apocalyptic (and dystopian) world where a phenomenon called the Digitalization gave humanity God-like power that led to their slow and eventual demise.<br>The player takes control of two main party members where they will navigate the world in a third person perspective.<br><br>Inspirations may take shape in different forms, from music to shows. Even art direction can be an inspiration. Here are the media that inspired Project Digitalization:<br><br><br>The Mario &amp; Luigi RPG series is a sub-series of role-playing video games developed by AlphaDream and published by Nintendo. The series is a spin-off of the Mario Bros. franchise and features Mario and Luigi as the main playable characters.<br><img alt="Pasted image 20241004213528.png" src="lib\media\pasted-image-20241004213528.png"><br>The games in the series are known for their unique blend of action-based combat and turn-based strategy, as well as their humorous writing and colorful visuals. The Mario &amp; Luigi RPG series has received praise for its innovative game play, memorable casts, charming humor, as well as a few nods to Nintendo’s history.<br>Project Digitalization will be utilizing the timed-based battle mechanics of the Mario &amp; Luigi RPG series for the main basis of the turn-based battle system. Normal attacks and the “Bros. Attacks” are used as a major reference. As for the flow of the battle system, certain aspects of it will be used in the project.<br><br><br>The Legend of Heroes: Trails through Daybreak is an action role-playing game by Nihon Falcom, marking the twelfth Trails series entry. Set in Calvard on the Zemurian continent, it features a mix of action and turn-based combat, letting players select their preferred battle system.<br><img alt="Pasted image 20241004213954.png" src="lib\media\pasted-image-20241004213954.png"><br><img alt="Pasted image 20241004214000.png" src="lib\media\pasted-image-20241004214000.png"><br>While primarily a turn-based game, the action battle system enables players to swiftly defeat enemies in seconds, circumventing lengthy turn-based encounters. Utilize the action battle system for weaker enemies, reserving turn-based combat for stronger foes (particularly bosses) to strategize and plan attacks effectively. You can change the battle system on-the-fly.<br>This will serve as Project Digitalization’s battle system flow.<br><br><img alt="scarlet-nexus-1.png" src="lib\media\scarlet-nexus-1.png"><br>SCARLET NEXUS is an action role-playing game developed and published by Bandai Namco Studios. The game is set in a futuristic “brain-punk” world where humanity is under attack from the Others, mysterious creatures that descended from the sky. Players take control of Yuito Sumeragi or Kasane Randall, new recruits of the Other Suppression Force (OSF), a military organization tasked with defending humanity from the Others.<br>The environments presented in SCARLET NEXUS will serve as a reference in Project Digitalization, with the biggest focus on the following environments in this Google Drive folder: <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://drive.google.com/drive/folders/1cZbtHVwU0k9SVwST04OX4bvYmu-M28hd?usp=sharing" rel="noopener" class="external-link" href="https://drive.google.com/drive/folders/1cZbtHVwU0k9SVwST04OX4bvYmu-M28hd?usp=sharing" target="_blank">SCARLET NEXUS Environments</a><br><br>The music from SCARLET NEXUS will also serve as a reference for the music style for Project Digitalization. The use of chiptune as a lead instrument alongside rock, electronic, and orchestral instruments give a futuristic yet gamey vibes.<br><br><img alt="Pasted image 20241004214352.png" src="lib\media\pasted-image-20241004214352.png"><br>Code Geass is a highly acclaimed anime series created by Sunrise and directed by Gorō Taniguchi. The show is renowned for its intricate plot, complex characters, and its exploration of themes such as power, morality, and rebellion. Set in a dystopian future where global factions vie for control, Code Geass follows Lelouch vi Britannia, a young man with the power to control others, as he orchestrates a revolution against an oppressive empire while grappling with his own moral dilemmas.<br>Project Digitalization draws significant inspiration from Code Geass in several key aspects. The game mirrors the anime's focus on a morally complex protagonist with God-like powers, who must navigate a world torn apart by his and others' actions. Like Lelouch, Bastian, the game's main character, leads a powerful organization and faces the challenge of balancing personal ambition with the broader consequences of his actions. The game incorporates similar themes of power, control, and the ethical struggles associated with wielding immense abilities.<br><br>The world is in chaos, torn apart by the misuse of Digitalization, a technology that grants humanity the power to create anything and bestow superhuman abilities upon themselves. Imperium Aeternum, a powerful organization, has taken control of Digitalization, enforcing its will on the shattered remnants of society. The Imperium played a crucial role in the event known as "The Shattering," a catastrophic moment when uncontrolled Digitalization led to the world's near-total destruction. They now rule the world with an iron fist, claiming to maintain order but often using their power for domination.<br>A weapon was created by a rogue faction to purge Digitalization from the world, believing that the only way to save humanity is to end the technology that has corrupted it. The Imperium seeks to control or destroy this weapon to prevent its use, as it would threaten their power.<br>The once-leader of Imperium Aeternum, Bastian was instrumental in the organization’s rise to power. After losing his memory during a rebel ambush, Bastian now unknowingly fights against his former comrades as he slowly regains his memories and discovers the truth about his past. As Bastian navigates the war-torn world, he encounters many faces both friend and foe alike on his journey, he must decide whether to reclaim his position within Imperium Aeternum, destroy the weapon to maintain their control, or activate it to end Digitalization, even if it means the end of the world.<br><br>This section aims to integrate a seamless transition between an action-based and turn-based combat system while incorporating timed-based attacks. The objective is to create a unique, immersive battle experience that combines the strategic depth of turn-based combat with the fast-paced, reflex-driven action found in real-time systems. This hybrid system will emphasize player skill and decision-making while maintaining the traditional tactical elements of turn-based gameplay.<br><br>
<br>Exploration Phase - While exploring the world, battle starts in real-time action mode. The player controls the main character and can engage in minor skirmishes with enemies directly on the field.
<br>Dynamic Combat Shift - Upon engaging tougher enemies or bosses, the battle can smoothly transition into a turn-based mode after one of the characters was able to stun an enemy, or when the player chooses to initiate "Tactical Mode." This shift will occur dynamically without loading screens or hard stops, maintaining immersion.
<br>Situational Awareness - Players can opt to enter turn-based combat manually or continue fighting in real-time for weaker enemies, blending styles based on tactical needs or personal preference.
<br><br>
<br>Action Commands - During the turn-based combat, player can execute timed attacks and defense attacks similar to the mechanics in Mario &amp; Luigi RPG series.

<br>Timed Attack Inputs - Pressing a button dedicated to one of the characters at the right moment will grant the characters additional benefits such as dealing more damage or chaining multiple attacks.

<br>Timed Defense Inputs - Pressing a button dedicated to one of the characters at the right moment during an enemy’s attack phase will allow the characters to dodge the attack or even counter-attack.




<br>Special Skills - Unique abilities can also involve quick-time events (QTEs) where precise inputs from involved characters during an animation enhances the move’s effects.
<br>Character Synergy - Certain characters can have group or combo attacks which also involve timed inputs from the involved characters, rewarding teamwork with more powerful moves when executed correctly.
<br><br>
<br>Momentum System - The system will feature a momentum gauge that builds up during the action phase. This gauge carries over into turn-based combat, allowing players to use it as a resource for special moves, combos, or powerful group attacks when transitioning to a turn-based battle.
<br>Action Influence on Turn-Based Combat - Decisions made during the action phase can affect the flow of the subsequent turn-based battle. Factors such as weakening the enemy and team positioning may bring advantages and even disadvantages during battle.
<br><br>
<br>On-Screen Indicators - The battle HUD will adapt dynamically depending on whether the player is in action or turn-based combat. In real-time combat, an action bar will appear that shows cooldowns, stamina, and available skills, while in turn-based combat, it will switch to show turn order and command menus.
<br>Audio and Visual Cues - Timing for action-based attacks will be highlighted by visual and audio cues, making it intuitive for players to engage with timed inputs while also giving the enemies some personality.
]]></description><link>documents\game-design-document.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Documents/Game Design Document.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 13:47:52 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="lib\media\pasted-image-20241004213528.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;lib\media\pasted-image-20241004213528.png&quot;&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Definitions]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>This Music License Agreement (the "Agreement") is made and entered into as of September 14, 2024, by and between:<br>
<br>Marc Victor Velasquez , residing in the Philippines and the United States of America (hereinafter referred to as the "Composer"), and
<br>Adrienne Clark Atim, the director of the game Project Digitalization, residing in the Philippines (hereinafter referred to as the "Licensee").
<br><br>
<br>Game: Refers to the video game currently titled "Project Digitalization" being developed by the Licensee.
<br>Music: Refers to the musical compositions and sound recordings created by the Composer specifically for the Game's soundtrack.
<br><br>The Composer hereby grants to the Licensee a non-exclusive, worldwide, perpetual license to use the Music solely in connection with the Game. This license includes the following rights:<br>
<br>Synchronization: The right to synchronize the Music with the Game's visual elements.
<br>Public Performance: The right to publicly perform the Music as part of the Game.
<br>Promotion: The right to use the Music in trailers, demos, and other marketing materials for the Game.
<br><br>The Licensee shall not:<br>
<br>Sell, license, or distribute the Music separately from the Game, except for the commercial distribution of the soundtrack through the game storefront where the Game is sold.
<br>Alter, remix, or modify the Music without the Composer's prior written consent.
<br>Use the Music in any other project or context outside of the Game and its promotional materials.
<br><br>The Licensee shall provide credit to the Composer in the Game's credits and any associated materials where music credits are typically displayed. The credit shall be in the following format: "Music by Marc Velasquez".<br><br>The Licensee is not required to compensate the Composer, @Marc Victor Velasquez, upon execution of this Agreement.<br><br>The Composer retains ownership of all copyrights in the Music. This Agreement does not transfer ownership of any copyrights to the Licensee.<br><br>This Agreement shall remain in effect in perpetuity unless terminated in accordance with this section. Either party may terminate this Agreement upon written notice to the other party if the other party materially breaches any term of this Agreement and fails to cure such breach within thirty (30) days after receiving written notice of the breach.<br><br>Both parties agree to take responsibility for any problems they cause by not following this agreement. If one party (the "Responsible Party") breaks the agreement and this leads to issues, costs, or legal troubles for the other party (the "Affected Party"), the Responsible Party will cover these costs and protect the Affected Party from harm.<br><br>This Agreement shall be governed by and construed in accordance with the laws of both the Philippines and the United States of America, as applicable to each party's respective jurisdiction. In the event of any conflict between the laws of these two countries, the parties agree to negotiate in good faith to resolve the issue. Any dispute arising out of or in connection with this Agreement that cannot be resolved through negotiation shall be subject to binding arbitration. The arbitration shall be conducted in English and held in a mutually agreed upon location, with the arbitrator(s) applying the substantive laws of both the Philippines and the United States as appropriate.<br><br>If any provision of this Agreement is held to be invalid or unenforceable, such provision shall be struck from the Agreement and the remaining provisions shall remain in full force and effect.<br><br>This Agreement constitutes the entire agreement between the parties with respect to the subject matter hereof and supersedes all prior or contemporaneous communications and proposals, whether oral or written.<br><br>IN WITNESS WHEREOF, the parties have executed this Agreement as of the date first above written.<br>@Marc Victor Velasquez<br>
Composer  <br>@Adrienne Clark Atim<br>
Licensee]]></description><link>documents\music-license-agreement.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Documents/Music License Agreement.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 13:52:23 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Project Pitch]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>Here are the presentation files, available for download:<br>
<br><a class="internal-link" data-href="CPP.pdf" href="attachments\pdf\cpp.pdf" target="_self" rel="noopener">Communist Programmer's Party Project Pitch Presentation PDF</a>
<br><a class="internal-link" data-href="CPP.pptx" href="attachments\powerpoint\cpp.pptx" target="_self" rel="noopener">Communist Programmer's Party Project Pitch Presentation PPTX</a>
]]></description><link>documents\project-pitch.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Documents/Project Pitch.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 14:00:20 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[High Level Requirements]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br><br>The game shall deliver a dynamic and fluid action-based combat system alongside a strategic and timed turn-based combat system, allowing players to utilize their skills through strategy and well-timed inputs. AI behavior should adjust based on player actions, and boss battles should provide escalating challenges with distinct phases and mechanics that engage players continuously.<br><br>The game shall feature an expansive open world that reflects the game’s unique visual style and lore. Players should be able to explore diverse environments that offer a sense of freedom and discovery. Interactive elements such as hidden areas and environmental storytelling, will enhance exploration. The world shall be populated with dynamics NPCs and a day-night cycle that responds to player action, contributing to the immersion and ensuring the world feels alive and reactive.<br><br>The game shall offer a branching narrative where player decisions have meaningful consequences on both the main story’s direction and character relationships. The narrative should encourage on both multiple playthroughs by offering divergent paths, multiple endings, and a New Game+ mode that unlocks additional content or altered storylines. Player choices should influence key events, leading to unique character arcs, alternative outcomes, and evolving world states that encourage players to experiment with different decision-making approaches.<br><br>The game shall provide incentives for multiple playthroughs by incorporating a range of replayability features such as achievements, hidden contents, and collectibles that encourage exploration and mastery of different aspects of the game. New Game+ should offer added challenges, enhanced difficulty, or new items that carry over from previous playthroughs. Additionally, certain story elements and world interactions should only be available on repeat playthroughs, offering players new perspectives and deeper understanding of the game’s world and characters.<br>The game shall also incorporate rogue-lite elements to enhance replayability and provide a unique experience in each playthrough. These elements include unlocking permanent character upgrades as well as run-based stat buffs, and some implementation of the <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://bulbapedia.bulbagarden.net/wiki/Nuzlocke_Challenge" rel="noopener" class="external-link" href="https://bulbapedia.bulbagarden.net/wiki/Nuzlocke_Challenge" target="_blank">nuzlocke system</a>.<br><br><br>The game shall allow players to transition smoothly between action-based and turn-based combat modes during battles without loading screens or interruptions The system will ensure a fluid gameplay experience where the switch is intuitive and does not disrupt the pacing of the combat. Transitions should be accompanied by visual and audio cues to indicate the change while maintaining performance stability.<br>It shall also be optimized to run smoothly on all supported platforms without significant frame drops, stuttering, or latency issues that could disrupt the player experience. Optimization efforts will include careful asset management, efficient resource loading, and well-designed animation systems to ensure high performance even in graphically intensive scenes or during complex combat sequences.<br><br>The game shall provide multiple difficulty settings to accommodate players of varying skill levels, from casual to experienced. Difficulty levels will influence enemy AI behavior, damage scaling, and overall combat challenge. In easier difficulties, combat should focus more on exploration and narrative, with simplified mechanics. While in harder difficulties, players will face more aggressive and intelligent enemies, requiring advanced strategies, positioning, and timing for success.  <br><br>The game shall include a variety of accessibility options to accommodate players with different needs. These will include customizable controls (e.g., remappable keys, controller support), adjustable difficulty settings for specific aspects of gameplay (such as timing windows for attacks or puzzles), subtitles with scalable text size and color contrast options, and visual/audio aids to support players with visual or auditory impairments. Additionally, features like colorblind modes and input latency adjustments will be considered to enhance inclusivity.]]></description><link>documents\requirements-engineering.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Documents/Requirements Engineering.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 14:26:51 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Project Title]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Shattered Eternity<br><br><br>To provide players with a combat system that seamlessly blends action and turn-based elements, set within a futuristic yet apocalyptic world.<br><br><br>
<br>Engaging Combat Experience - The game shall deliver a dynamic and fluid action-based combat system alongside a strategic and timed turn-based combat system, allowing players to utilize their skills through strategy and well-timed inputs. AI behavior should adjust based on player actions, and boss battles should provide escalating challenges with distinct phases and mechanics that engage players continuously.
<br>Immersive World Design - The game shall feature an expansive open world that reflects the game’s unique visual style and lore. Players should be able to explore diverse environments that offer a sense of freedom and discovery. Interactive elements such as hidden areas and environmental storytelling, will enhance exploration. The world shall be populated with dynamics NPCs and a day-night cycle that responds to player action, contributing to the immersion and ensuring the world feels alive and reactive.
<br>Impactful Narrative and Meaningful Choices - The game shall offer a branching narrative where player decisions have meaningful consequences on both the main story’s direction and character relationships. The narrative should encourage multiple playthroughs by offering divergent paths, multiple endings, and a New Game+ mode that unlocks additional content or altered storylines. Player choices should influence key events, leading to unique character arcs, alternative outcomes, and evolving world states that encourage players to experiment with different decision-making approaches.
<br>Replayability and Player Incentives - The game shall provide incentives for multiple playthroughs by incorporating a range of replayability features such as achievements, hidden contents, and collectibles that encourage exploration and mastery of different aspects of the game. New Game+ should offer added challenges, enhanced difficulty, or new items that carry over from previous playthroughs. Additionally, certain story elements and world interactions should only be available on repeat playthroughs, offering players new perspectives and deeper understanding of the game’s world and characters. The game shall also incorporate rogue-lite elements to enhance replayability and provide a unique experience in each playthrough. These elements include unlocking permanent character upgrades as well as run-based stat buffs, and some implementation of the <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://bulbapedia.bulbagarden.net/wiki/Nuzlocke_Challenge" rel="noopener" class="external-link" href="https://bulbapedia.bulbagarden.net/wiki/Nuzlocke_Challenge" target="_blank">nuzlocke system</a>.
<br><br>
<br>Performance - The game shall allow players to transition smoothly between action-based and turn-based combat modes during battles without loading screens or interruptions The system will ensure a fluid gameplay experience where the switch is intuitive and does not disrupt the pacing of the combat. Transitions should be accompanied by visual and audio cues to indicate the change while maintaining performance stability. It shall also be optimized to run smoothly on all supported platforms without significant frame drops, stuttering, or latency issues that could disrupt the player experience. Optimization efforts will include careful asset management, efficient resource loading, and well-designed animation systems to ensure high performance even in graphically intensive scenes or during complex combat sequences.
<br>Combat System Settings - The game shall provide multiple difficulty settings to accommodate players of varying skill levels, from casual to experienced. Difficulty levels will influence enemy AI behavior, damage scaling, and overall combat challenge. In easier difficulties, combat should focus more on exploration and narrative, with simplified mechanics. While in harder difficulties, players will face more aggressive and intelligent enemies, requiring advanced strategies, positioning, and timing for success.
<br>Accessibility - The game shall include a variety of accessibility options to accommodate players with different needs. These will include customizable controls (e.g., remappable keys, controller support), adjustable difficulty settings for specific aspects of gameplay (such as timing windows for attacks or puzzles), subtitles with scalable text size and color contrast options, and visual/audio aids to support players with visual or auditory impairments. Additionally, features like colorblind modes and input latency adjustments will be considered to enhance inclusivity.
<br><br>
<br>Potential Backers - Individuals or organizations considering financial support for the project. This audience will be interested in understanding the game’s unique value proposition, target market, and overall potential for return on investment.
<br>Game Development Team - This includes developers, designers, artists, and project managers who will rely on the SRS to align their work with the project's objectives. Clear requirements will help them understand their roles and deliverables.
<br>Community and Fans - While not the primary audience for the SRS, informed fans and community members may find value in understanding the game’s vision and development process, which can foster their engagement and support for the project.
<br><br>Project Digitalization is an innovative hybrid action and turn-based RPG set in a post-apocalyptic world. The game aims to deliver a unique gaming experience by seamlessly blending fast-paced action combat with strategic turn-based encounters, all wrapped in a compelling narrative that responds to player choices.<br>Key objectives and benefits include:<br>
<br>Engaging players with a dynamic combat system that combines real-time action and turn-based strategy, appealing to a wide range of RPG enthusiasts.
<br>Immersing players in a richly detailed world with a complex, branching narrative that encourages multiple playthroughs and fosters community discussions.
<br>Providing a fresh take on the RPG genre by incorporating innovative mechanics inspired by successful games and anime series, setting the game apart in a competitive market.
<br>Offering high replayability through multiple endings, New Game+ features, and rogue-lite elements, ensuring long-term player engagement and potential for additional content.
<br>From a business perspective, Project Digitalization aligns with our corporate goals by:<br>
<br>Establishing our studio as a creator of unique, high-quality gaming experiences that push the boundaries of traditional genre definitions.
<br>Targeting a diverse player base, from casual gamers to hardcore RPG fans, potentially expanding our market reach and increasing revenue streams.
<br>Creating opportunities for post-launch content and potential franchise development, supporting long-term business growth and sustainability.
<br>Showcasing our technical expertise in seamlessly blending different combat systems, positioning our studio as innovative developers in the gaming industry.
<br><br>SCARLET NEXUS<br>
<br>Source: Video Game
<br>Platforms: PlayStation 4, PlayStation 5, Xbox One, Xbox Series X/S, PC (via Steam)
<br>Description: A sci-fi action RPG set in a futuristic world where humans coexist with alien creatures called Others. Players take on the role of Yuito Sumeragi or Kasane Randall, members of a special unit tasked with protecting humanity from Others.
<br>Solar Ash<br>
<br>Source: Video Game
<br>Platforms: PlayStation 4, PlayStation 5, Nintendo Switch, PC (via Epic Games Store)
<br>Description: A third-person action-adventure game where players control Rei, a Voidrider, who must journey through a surreal, colorful world to save their planet from a black hole. The game features fast-paced combat, exploration, and platforming.
<br>Code Geass: Lelouch of the Rebellion S1 &amp; S2<br>
<br>Source: Anime Series
<br>Platforms: Various streaming services (e.g., Netflix, Crunchyroll)
<br>Description: A mecha anime series set in a dystopian future where the Holy Britannian Empire has conquered much of the world. The story follows Lelouch vi Britannia, a exiled prince who gains the power of absolute obedience (Geass) and vows to destroy the Britannian Empire.
<br>Persona 5 Royal<br>
<br>Source: Video Game
<br>Platforms: PlayStation 4, PlayStation 5, Xbox One, Nintendo Switch, PC (via Steam)
<br>Description: A Japanese role-playing game where players take on the role of a high school student who gains the ability to enter the Metaverse, a parallel world where people's desires and fears manifest. The game combines dungeon crawling, social simulation, and turn-based combat.
<br>The Legend of Heroes: Trails through Daybreak<br>
<br>Source: Video Game
<br>Platforms: PlayStation 4, PlayStation 5, Nintendo Switch, PC (via Steam)
<br>Description: A role-playing game set in the Trails series. The story follows a group of adventurers who must uncover a conspiracy that threatens the peace of the continent of Calvard. The game features a deep and engaging narrative, turn-based combat, and character development.
<br><br><br>Project Digitalization is a unique action RPG that combines elements from various successful games and anime series to create a fresh and engaging experience. The game draws inspiration from the following key sources:<br>
<br>Combat System: Inspired by The Legend of Heroes: Trails through Daybreak, the game features a dynamic combat system that seamlessly blends action-based and turn-based elements. This hybrid approach allows for both fast-paced, real-time battles and strategic, thoughtful encounters.
<br>World Design: Taking cues from Solar Ash, the game presents a visually striking and surreal world that encourages exploration and discovery. The environment is designed to be both beautiful and integral to the gameplay experience.
<br>Narrative Structure: Drawing from the complex storytelling of Code Geass, Project Digitalization offers a multi-layered plot with political intrigue, personal conflicts, and moral dilemmas. The narrative adapts to player choices, leading to multiple possible outcomes.
<br>World-Building and Lore: Following the example set by The Legend of Heroes series, Project Digitalization features a rich, detailed world with its own history, politics, and cultural nuances that players can gradually uncover throughout their journey.
<br>By combining these elements, Project Digitalization aims to create a unique gaming experience that stands out in the action RPG genre. The game will offer players a deep, immersive world to explore, a compelling narrative that responds to their choices, and a combat system that rewards both quick reflexes and tactical thinking.<br><br>
<br>A hybrid of an action and turn-based combat system.
<br>A dystopian yet vibrant open-world environment
<br>Rogue-lite elements such as a nuzlocke system.
<br><br>
<br>RPG players who played games like Honkai Star Rails, Persona series, Final Fantasy, and more.
<br>Action players who played games like the Kingdom Hearts series, Devil May Cry series, Genshin Impact, and more.
<br><br>The software will be operational on a Windows-based operating system, with the minimum version being Windows 10 (Steam no longer supports Windows versions below Windows 10). A Linux version of the software is also being considered.<br>As for portable handheld PCs such as the Steam Deck and the ASUS ROG Ally, the Windows version will do for operating the software.<br><br>
<br>The rendering of game objects of the software should still be visible even though the graphical quality of the software is adjusted by the users.
<br>There is no budget for the development of this software as of the writing of this SRS. Because of this, localization of the software is not possible. The only language supported by the software in terms of its UI, dialogue, and audio is English.
<br><br>The user will be able to learn how to operate the software/game through the tutorials presented in the game. The control scheme will also be visible via the Options/Settings screen (with a visualization of the controller as well).<br><br>
<br>The licensing agreement could change on the game engine used which is Unity. In September 2023, Unity changed their licensing which led to the market share of Unity to drop. The market share of Unity will also affect its licensing in the future.
<br>The project will be migrating from Unity 2022 to Unity 6 by the time it will be released. The development team assumes that the project transition will be smooth since the Unity engine has a tool to migrate projects from older versions.
<br>The music composer does not have a legal license for FL Studio, and will be using a pirated copy instead. It is assumed that the music composer will be acquiring a legal license once the development of the software reaches its conclusion.
<br><br><br><img alt="prototype-ui-1.png" src="lib\media\prototype-ui-1.png"><br><img alt="prototype-ui-2.png" src="lib\media\prototype-ui-2.png"><br><br>Main Device<br>
<br>Windows 10 (or later) desktop or laptop
<br>Portable handheld PCs such as the Steam Deck, ASUS ROG Ally
<br>Accessories<br>
<br>Wired/wireless mouse
<br>Wired/wireless keyboard
<br>DualShock 4 controller
<br>DualSense controller
<br>Xbox One controller
<br>Xbox Series controller
<br><br>Operating System<br>
<br>Windows 10/Windows 11 - The game will be optimized for these operating systems, ensuring smooth performance and compatibility with a wide range of hardware configurations. Regular updates and patches will be released to address any OS-specific issues and take advantage of new features or optimizations in Windows.
<br>Debian-based Linux - Linux is also being considered as an additional platform for the project. Because of this, testing will also be done on a Debian-based Linux operating system like Ubuntu or Linux Mint.
<br>Tools<br>
<br>Unity Engine - The game will be developed with the Unity game engine version 2022, with the intention to migrate to Unity 6 once it releases later in 2024. It will be utilizing the Universal Rendering Pipeline.
<br>Visual Studio Code - Visual Studio Code will be used as the primary integrated development environment (IDE) for writing and editing code. Its extensive plugin ecosystem, Git integration, and debugging capabilities make it an ideal choice for efficient development workflow. The team will utilize VS Code's collaboration features to streamline code reviews and pair programming sessions.
<br>Blender - Blender will be used for 3D modeling, animation, and rendering of game assets. Its open-source nature and powerful features make it an ideal choice for creating high-quality visual elements that align with the game's unique art style. The 3D models and animations created in Blender will be exported and integrated into the Unity engine for use in the game.
<br>FL Studio - FL Studio will be used for music composition, sound design, and audio production. Its versatile tools and intuitive interface make it ideal for creating the game's soundtrack, sound effects, and atmospheric audio. The audio assets produced in FL Studio will be exported and integrated into Unity to create an immersive audio experience that complements the game's visual style and gameplay.
<br><br>The software will be utilizing Steam’s API to recognize certain activities based from the user’s activity in order to grant players different achievements.<br><br><br>The game will include an autosave feature to minimize progress loss in case of unexpected interruptions, such as power outages, crashes, or player exits.<br><br>The game will have customizable key binds to cater to the different preferences of all players.<br><br>The game will offer a multitude of settings for the players to fine-tune their experience while playing the game.<br><br>The game will provide support for controllers to enhance accessibility and broaden the player base.<br><br><br>Minimum System Requirements<br>
<br>CPU: Intel i5-8365U
<br>GPU: Nvidia GT 730
<br>RAM: 8GB DDR4
<br>Storage: TBD
<br>Operating System: Windows 10 and later
<br>Recommended System Requirements<br>
<br>CPU: Intel i5-12400
<br>GPU: Nvidia GeForce GTX 1050 Ti
<br>RAM: 16GB DDR4
<br>Storage: TBD
<br>Operating System: Windows 10 and later
<br><br>The game will implement an “auto-save” feature that automatically saves player progress at regular intervals or key moments, ensuring that players do not lose significant progress in the event of unexpected interruptions (e.g., power loss, crashes, or player exits).<br><br>The game will be published on the Steam marketplace, utilizing Steam's DRM as its security measure. This DRM will prevent unauthorized access to copies of the software.<br><br>The game will be made to be as optimized as possible making it accessible to a wide range of devices. It will also go through multiple phases of testing to make sure that it is robust.<br><br>
<br>Adrienne Clark Atim - Game Director, Level Designer, Developer  
<br>Marc Victor Velasquez - Producer, Tech Lead, 3D Artist, Environment Designer, Music Composer 
<br>Ivan David - Story Writer Assistant, Developer  
<br>Aris Justine Dizon - Quality Assurance, Level Designer, Developer
]]></description><link>documents\software-requirements-specifications.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Documents/Software Requirements Specifications.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 14:38:16 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="lib\media\prototype-ui-1.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;lib\media\prototype-ui-1.png&quot;&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Game Engine]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>The game will be developed utilizing the Unity game engine, a powerful and versatile platform for creating interactive experiences. Our team has chosen Unity for its robust features, extensive asset store, and cross-platform capabilities. We have plans to transition to Unity 6 upon its official release on October 17, 2024, which will allow us to take advantage of the latest improvements and optimizations offered by this major update.<br>In terms of rendering technology, we will be implementing the Universal Rendering Pipeline (URP). This choice was made deliberately to ensure optimal performance across a wide range of devices while maintaining high-quality visuals. The URP offers a balance between graphical fidelity and efficiency, making it ideal for our project's requirements.<br>Currently, our development efforts are focused on creating and refining Unity game objects, with particular emphasis on two critical components: character models and the camera system. The character development process involves intricate modeling, rigging, and animation to bring our game's protagonists and NPCs to life. Simultaneously, we are fine-tuning the camera system to provide smooth, intuitive player perspectives that enhance the overall gaming experience. These elements form the foundation of our game's visual and interactive aspects, and their ongoing development is crucial to achieving our desired gameplay mechanics and aesthetic goals.<br><br>For the creation of 3D assets, we will be utilizing Blender, a powerful open-source 3D modeling and animation software. Blender offers a comprehensive suite of tools that will enable us to create high-quality, optimized 3D models for our game.<br>Key aspects of our Blender workflow include:<br>
<br>Low-poly modeling: We'll focus on creating efficient, low-polygon models to ensure smooth performance across various platforms.
<br>UV unwrapping: Proper UV mapping will be crucial for applying textures effectively to our 3D models.
<br>Rigging and animation: Character rigs and animations will be created directly in Blender, taking advantage of its robust animation toolset. Although for animating some of the complex scenes in the game, the team will be using Unity’s animation system
<br>Export pipeline: We'll establish a streamlined export process from Blender to Unity, ensuring proper scale, orientation, and material settings.
<br>By leveraging Blender's capabilities, we aim to create visually appealing and performance-optimized 3D assets that will enhance the overall quality of our game while maintaining compatibility with Unity's Universal Rendering Pipeline.<br><br>For the game's soundtrack, we will be utilizing FL Studio as our primary Digital Audio Workstation (DAW) along with FLEX plugins to create a rich and immersive musical experience. Here's an overview of our audio production process:<br>
<br>FL Studio: This versatile DAW will serve as the foundation for our music composition and production. Its intuitive interface and powerful features make it ideal for creating game soundtracks.
<br>FLEX Plugins: We'll leverage FLEX, FL Studio's powerful synthesizer, to generate a wide range of sounds. FLEX's extensive preset library and sound-shaping capabilities will allow us to create unique and atmospheric sounds tailored to our game's aesthetic.
<br>Custom Sound Design: Using FL Studio's native plugins and FLEX, we'll design custom sounds and instruments that align with our game's theme and setting.
<br>Adaptive Music System: We'll implement an adaptive music system using FL Studio's playlist feature, allowing the soundtrack to dynamically respond to in-game events and player actions.
<br>Mixing and Mastering: FL Studio's mixing console and mastering tools will be used to ensure high-quality audio output that translates well across different playback systems.
<br>By combining FL Studio's robust production environment with the versatility of FLEX plugins, we aim to create a captivating and dynamic soundtrack that enhances the player's immersion and complements the game's visual elements.]]></description><link>documents\technical-specifications.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Documents/Technical Specifications.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 13:51:39 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Tools]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br><img alt="unity-banner-1.png" src="lib\media\unity-banner-1.png"><br>Unity is a powerful and versatile game development engine that enables creators to bring their ideas to life. With its intuitive interface and extensive feature set, Unity has become a go-to platform for both indie developers and large studios alike. From 2D mobile games to immersive 3D experiences, Unity provides the tools necessary to craft engaging interactive content across various platforms.<br>Note that Shattered Eternity will be using Unity 6 for the development of the project. However, the prototype will be developed with Unity 2022 which will allow its developers to prepare the essential game objects ahead of the Unity 6 release on October 17, 2024.<br>Installation for Windows<br>
To install Unity on Windows, follow these steps:<br>
<br>Visit the official Unity website (<a rel="noopener" class="external-link" href="https://unity.com/" target="_blank">https://unity.com/</a>).
<br>Click on the "Get Started" button.
<br>Choose "Individual" plan (free for personal use). You may also apply for the Educational license, which will grant you additional assets (although it is not necessary).
<br>Click "Download Unity Hub".
<br>Run the Unity Hub installer and follow the on-screen instructions.
<br>Once Unity Hub is installed, open it.
<br>In Unity Hub, go to the "Installs" tab.
<br>Click "Add" to install a new Unity version. For this project, you will be using Unity 6 Preview. However, on October 17, 2024, you will need to install the official release of Unity 6 (different from Unity 6 Preview).
<br>Select the latest Long Term Support (LTS) version for stability.
<br>Choose the modules you need (e.g., Windows Build Support).
<br>Click "Install" and wait for the process to complete.<br>
After installation, you can create new projects or open existing ones through Unity Hub. Remember to regularly check for updates to ensure you have the latest features and bug fixes.
<br><br><img alt="Pasted image 20241006232802.png" src="lib\media\pasted-image-20241006232802.png"><br>Obsidian.md is a powerful note-taking app that lets you build a connected web of your thoughts. Unlike traditional apps, it uses Markdown files for notes, allowing for easy formatting and flexibility. The key feature is the ability to link notes together, creating a visual map of your ideas and making it easy to see connections. With its focus on privacy and customization, Obsidian is a great tool for anyone who wants to organize their knowledge in a non-linear way.<br>Installation (Windows)<br>
<br>Download the application on Obsidian's website.
<br>Once the download is complete, locate the downloaded .exe and double-click it to run the installer.
<br>Read the license agreement and click "Next" to proceed.
<br>Select the desired installation directory or accept the default location and click "Next."
<br>If you want to add "Open with Code" to the Windows Explorer context menu or configure other settings, check the desired options and click "Next."
<br>Begin the installation process by clicking "Install" to start the installation process.
<br>Once the installation is finished, click "Finish" to close the installer.
<br><br><img alt="vscode-banner-1.png" src="lib\media\vscode-banner-1.png"><br>Visual Studio Code (VS Code) is a lightweight yet powerful source code editor developed by Microsoft. It has gained immense popularity among developers due to its speed, extensibility, and rich ecosystem of extensions. VS Code supports a wide range of programming languages and frameworks, making it an ideal choice for various development tasks, from web development to data science.<br>Installation from Website (Windows)<br>
To install Visual Studio Code on Windows, follow these steps:<br>
<br>Visit the official Visual Studio Code website (<a rel="noopener" class="external-link" href="https://code.visualstudio.com/" target="_blank">https://code.visualstudio.com/</a>)
<br>Click on the "Download for Windows" button
<br>Once the installer is downloaded, run the .exe file
<br>Accept the license agreement and click "Next"
<br>Choose the installation location (or leave the default) and click "Next"
<br>Select additional tasks if desired (e.g., adding "Open with Code" action to Windows Explorer context menu) and click "Next"
<br>Click "Install" to begin the installation process
<br>Once installation is complete, click "Finish"
<br>Visual Studio Code should now be installed on your Windows system. You can launch it from the Start menu or desktop shortcut if you created one during installation. After installation, you may want to customize VS Code by installing extensions relevant to your development needs. You can do this by clicking on the Extensions icon in the left sidebar (or press Ctrl+Shift+X) and searching for extensions by name or programming language.<br>Visual Studio Code Extensions<br>
Here are some of the extensions necessary for the development of Shattered Eternity:<br>
<br>Unity - This extension provides IntelliSense, debugging, and other Unity-specific features for C# development in VS Code. It enhances the coding experience for Unity projects by offering code completion, syntax highlighting, and integration with Unity's console output.
<br>C# Dev Kit - Offers rich support for C# development, including syntax highlighting, IntelliSense, and debugging capabilities. This is essential for scripting in Unity projects.
<br>Live Share - Enables real-time collaborative coding sessions, allowing multiple developers to work on the same project simultaneously. This extension is particularly useful for remote pair programming or team code reviews, enhancing productivity and knowledge sharing within the development team.
<br><br><img alt="git-banner-1.png" src="lib\media\git-banner-1.png"><br>Git is a distributed version control system that has become an essential tool for software development and collaboration. Created by Linus Torvalds in 2005, Git allows developers to track changes in their code, manage different versions, and collaborate seamlessly with team members. Its distributed nature means that each developer has a full copy of the project's history, enabling offline work and providing a robust backup system.<br>Key features of Git include:<br>
<br>Branching and merging: Easily create separate lines of development and combine them later
<br>Staging area: Review and organize changes before committing
<br>Speed and efficiency: Optimized for handling large projects
<br>Data integrity: Uses cryptographic hashing to ensure the consistency of project history
<br>Git's popularity has led to the rise of platforms like GitHub, GitLab, and Bitbucket, which provide additional collaboration features and cloud-based repositories. These platforms have further cemented Git's role as an indispensable tool in modern software development workflows.<br>Installation (Windows)<br>
To install Git on Windows, follow these steps:<br>
<br>Visit the official Git website (<a rel="noopener" class="external-link" href="https://git-scm.com/" target="_blank">https://git-scm.com/</a>)
<br>Click on the "Download for Windows" button
<br>The download should start automatically. If not, click on the manual download link
<br>Once the installer is downloaded, run the .exe file
<br>Review and accept the GNU General Public License
<br>Choose the installation location (or leave the default) and click "Next"
<br>Select the components you want to install (the default selection is usually sufficient)
<br>Choose the default editor used by Git (you can change this later)
<br>Adjust your PATH environment if necessary (the recommended option is usually best)
<br>Choose the SSH executable and HTTPS transport backend
<br>Configure the line ending conversions (the recommended setting is usually best)
<br>Choose the terminal emulator to use with Git Bash
<br>Configure extra options as desired
<br>Click "Install" to begin the installation process
<br>Once installation is complete, click "Finish"
<br>After installation, you can verify that Git is installed correctly by opening a command prompt or Git Bash and typing git --version. This should display the installed version of Git.<br><br><img alt="github-banner-1.png" src="lib\media\github-banner-1.png"><br>GitHub Desktop is a user-friendly application that simplifies the process of working with Git and GitHub. Developed by GitHub, this graphical interface tool provides an intuitive way to manage repositories, commit changes, and collaborate with others without the need for command-line operations. It's particularly useful for those new to version control or developers who prefer a visual approach to managing their projects.<br>Key features of GitHub Desktop include:<br>
<br>Easy repository cloning and creation
<br>Visual diff tool for reviewing changes
<br>Simplified branching and merging
<br>Seamless integration with <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="http://github.com/" rel="noopener" class="external-link" href="http://github.com/" target="_blank">GitHub.com</a>
<br>Built-in merge conflict resolution
<br>GitHub Desktop serves as an excellent bridge between the powerful capabilities of Git and the collaborative features of GitHub, making version control more accessible to a wider range of users.<br>Installation (Windows)<br>
To install GitHub Desktop on Windows, follow these steps:<br>
<br>Visit the official GitHub Desktop website (<a rel="noopener" class="external-link" href="https://desktop.github.com/" target="_blank">https://desktop.github.com/</a>)
<br>Click on the "Download for Windows (64bit)" button
<br>Once the installer is downloaded, run the GitHubDesktopSetup.exe file
<br>The installation will begin automatically. Wait for it to complete
<br>When prompted, sign in to your GitHub account or create a new one
<br>Configure your name and email for Git commits
<br>Choose whether to submit anonymous usage data to help improve the application
<br>GitHub Desktop is now installed and ready to use.
<br>After installation, you can start using GitHub Desktop to clone repositories, make commits, and sync changes with GitHub. The application provides a helpful tutorial for new users to get familiar with its interface and basic operations.<br><br><img alt="blender-banner-1.png" src="lib\media\blender-banner-1.png"><br>Blender is a free and open-source 3D creation suite that has revolutionized the world of 3D modeling, animation, and rendering. With its comprehensive toolset and active community, Blender has become a favorite among artists, designers, and even game developers. From creating detailed 3D models to producing stunning visual effects, Blender offers a robust platform for bringing creative visions to life.<br>Installation (Windows)<br>
To install Blender on Windows, follow these steps:<br>
<br>Visit the official Blender website (<a rel="noopener" class="external-link" href="https://www.blender.org/" target="_blank">https://www.blender.org/</a>)
<br>Click on the "Download" button on the homepage
<br>Select the latest stable version for Windows
<br>Choose between the 64-bit installer or portable version (installer recommended for most users)
<br>Once the download is complete, run the installer
<br>Follow the on-screen instructions in the installation wizard
<br>Choose the installation location (or leave the default) and click "Next"
<br>Select additional options if desired (e.g., creating desktop shortcut) and click "Next"
<br>Click "Install" to begin the installation process
<br>Once installation is complete, click "Finish"
<br>Blender should now be installed on your Windows system. You can launch it from the Start menu or desktop shortcut if you created one during installation. After installation, it's recommended to check for any available updates to ensure you have the latest features and bug fixes. You can do this by going to Help &gt; Check for Updates in the Blender application.<br><br><img alt="fl-studio-banner-1.png" src="lib\media\fl-studio-banner-1.png"><br>FL Studio, developed by Image-Line, is a digital audio workstation (DAW) that has become a staple in music production. Known for its intuitive interface and powerful features, FL Studio caters to both beginners and professional musicians. The software offers a comprehensive suite of tools for composing, arranging, recording, editing, mixing, and mastering high-quality music.<br>Installation (Windows)<br>
To install FL Studio on Windows, follow these steps:<br>
<br>Visit the official FL Studio website (<a rel="noopener" class="external-link" href="https://www.image-line.com/" target="_blank">https://www.image-line.com/</a>)
<br>Click on the "Download" button in the top navigation menu
<br>Scroll down to find the "Download FL Studio" section
<br>Click on the "Download" button for the Windows version
<br>Once the installer is downloaded, run the .exe file
<br>If prompted by Windows security, click "Run" or "Yes" to allow the installation
<br>In the installation wizard, select your preferred language and click "OK"
<br>Read and accept the license agreement, then click "Next"
<br>Choose the installation type (Full or Custom) and click "Next"
<br>Select the installation location or leave the default, then click "Next"
<br>Choose whether to create desktop and start menu shortcuts, then click "Next"
<br>Click "Install" to begin the installation process
<br>Once installation is complete, click "Finish"
<br>After installation, you'll need to register your copy of FL Studio. If you've purchased a license, enter your account details when prompted. If you're using the trial version, you can explore the software's features for a limited time.<br>Note that FL Studio offers different editions with varying features. Make sure to choose the edition that best suits your needs and budget when purchasing a license. If you are installing a pirated copy of FL Studio, make sure to purchase it in the future. Support its developers as well.]]></description><link>guides\tools.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Guides/Tools.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 09:13:33 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="lib\media\unity-banner-1.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;lib\media\unity-banner-1.png&quot;&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Agenda]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br><br>
<br>Marc Velasquez introduced the project with its development name Project Digitalization. The commercial name will be determined by Adrienne Clark Atim later.&nbsp;
<br>Presented the initial story of the game where humanity gained God-like powers, leading to the nearing destruction of humankind.&nbsp;
<br>Displayed the references used for the proposal such as the Mario &amp; Luigi RPG series and Square Enix’s HD-2D art style.&nbsp;
<br>Presented the proposed gameplay style where it will replicate the combat of the Mario &amp; Luigi RPG series but with swappable weapons, which will allow more customization during combat.&nbsp;
<br><br>
<br>Ivan David suggested using Risk of Rain’s time difficulty mechanic where the longer the player is in a game session, the more difficult the enemies will be. This will encourage players to blaze through the game as soon as possible while also considering their strategy later in the game.&nbsp;
<br><br>
<br>Marc Velasquez proposes the Godot game engine (.NET version) to develop the game. Although the game engine is better off using its proprietary programming language, GDScript, the development team agreed to use a programming language that was familiar to them.
<br><br>
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="obsidian://open?vault=Project%20Digitalization&amp;file=attachments%2FWord%2FMeetings%2FProject%20Digitalization%20Meeting%20001%20-%20Onboarding%20Meeting%201.docx" rel="noopener" class="external-link" href="obsidian:\\open?vault=Project Digitalization&amp;file=attachments%2FWord%2FMeetings%2FProject Digitalization Meeting 001 - Onboarding Meeting 1.docx" target="_blank">Meeting 001 - Onboarding Meeting</a>
]]></description><link>meetings\meeting-001-onboarding-meeting.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Meetings/Meeting 001 - Onboarding Meeting.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2024 14:24:21 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Agenda&nbsp;]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br><br>
<br>Marc Velasquez suggested some changes to the direction of the main story. The following changes were proposed:&nbsp;
<br>First is the introduction to the concepts of the Digitalization phenomena where humanity claims where gifts from the beings above. This granted them God-like powers. However, due to humanity’s desire for more power, it ended up destroying their sense of humanity alongside the very world they live in.&nbsp;
<br>Second is the environmental storytelling will be an essential part of the main story. The world is filled with desolate environments but with a bit of cyberpunk aesthetic.&nbsp;
<br>Last are the beings (who are not human/s) that wander the world being those born from the Digitalization phenomena, whether it is born naturally from the phenomena or was created by humanity.&nbsp;
<br>Adrienne Atim also shared his progress regarding the story for Project Digitalization. The following progress were made:&nbsp;
<br>The world order of Project Digitalization will be faction-based, with two factions being the major players.&nbsp;
<br>The main protagonist of Project Digitalization is affiliated with one of the world’s factions.&nbsp;
<br>A summary of the story of the game through Project Digitalization’s game design document.&nbsp;
<br><br>
<br>Adrienne Atim suggested the references for two of the main characters for Project Digitalization:&nbsp;

<br>The male protagonist is based of Lelouch vi Britannia from the Japanese animation series Code Geass. The costume will also be like Lelouch vi Britannia from Code Geass alongside Joker from the Japanese video game Persona 5.&nbsp;
<br>The female character is based of Rei Ayanami from the Japanese animation series Neon Geneses Evangelion. Although the personality will be much bolder than the reference’s stoic personality at the beginning of the Japanese animation series. No references for the costumes were provided.&nbsp;


<br><br>
<br>Marc Velasquez commenced the development of the gameplay prototype with the Godot game engine (.NET version).&nbsp;
<br>The prototype will not contain the actual assets for the game since the focus is on the gameplay as well as developing the game’s toolkit.
<br><br>
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="obsidian://open?vault=Project%20Digitalization&amp;file=attachments%2FWord%2FMeetings%2FProject%20Digitalization%20Meeting%20002%20-%20Project%20Lead%20Meeting%201.docx" rel="noopener" class="external-link" href="obsidian:\\open?vault=Project Digitalization&amp;file=attachments%2FWord%2FMeetings%2FProject Digitalization Meeting 002 - Project Lead Meeting 1.docx" target="_blank">Meeting 002 - Project Lead Meeting 1</a>
]]></description><link>meetings\meeting-002-project-lead-meeting-1.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Meetings/Meeting 002 - Project Lead Meeting 1.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2024 13:46:07 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Agenda]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br><br>
<br>Marc Velasquez showed some of the references used for the development of Project Digitalization such as Square Enix’s Octopath Traveler and Arc System’s River City Girls and River City Girls 2.&nbsp;
<br><br>
<br>Adrienne Atim requested if it is possible to go full-3D on the game, ditching the 2D sprites of the characters and certain environmental elements.&nbsp;
<br>Marc Velasquez presented the possible art style to use. A 3D model that is akin the polygon counts of the Nintendo 64 and the original PlayStation 1.&nbsp;
<br><br>
<br>Adrienne Atim suggested the removal of the timed-based attacks from the Mario &amp; Luigi RPG series and instead go for Atlus’ Persona battle system. Aspects such as the positioning of the characters as well as the camera angles and positions are some of the elements Adrienne Atim would like to implement for Project Digitalization.&nbsp;
<br>The suggestions can still be modified according to Adrienne Atim.
]]></description><link>meetings\meeting-003-project-idea-meeting-1.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Meetings/Meeting 003 - Project Idea Meeting 1.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 14:48:34 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Agenda]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br><br>
<br>Marc Velasquez, the producer of Project Digitalization, has decided to prepare a development setup with Arch Linux. The hardware being used is Sony’s PlayStation 4.
<br>Adrienne Atim guided the producer on the procedures of installing the customized operating system on the video game console (now turned development setup).
<br>The installation ended in failure due to the lack of tools needed to install the Unity game engine.
<br><br>
<br>The minimum system requirements will be based on the development system of Adrienne Atim in terms of the GPU, RAM capacity, and Windows operating system while the CPU minimum requirements is based on Marc Velasquez’s current development system (not referring to the PlayStation 4).
<br>The recommended system requirements will be based on the development system of Ivan David.
]]></description><link>meetings\meeting-004-development-machine-setup-1.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Meetings/Meeting 004 - Development Machine Setup 1.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2024 00:23:08 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Agenda]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br><br>
<br>All members of the development team worked on the software requirements specifications as part of an academic requirement due on the same day.
<br>The creation of new information was minimized since the project specifications and game design document was already prepared beforehand.
<br><br>
<br>Aris Justine Dizon proposed multiple variants for the project name based on the contents of the game design document such as: Shattered Realities, The Purge of Digitalization, Echoes of the Imperium, Bastian’s Awakening, The Weight of Power, Digital Ruins, Chaos and Redemption, The Last Weapon, Fractured Memories, Fate of the Aeternum, Dawn of the Shattered, The Digital Reckoning, Legacy of Control, Rise of the Rogue, Aeternum’s Fall, The Memory of Power, Broken Bonds, Endgame of the Imperium, A World Unmade, and The Last Stand of Humanity.
<br>Adrienne Atim has determined the commercial project name: Shattered Eternity.
]]></description><link>meetings\meeting-005-software-requirements-specifications-1.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Meetings/Meeting 005 - Software Requirements Specifications 1.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2024 00:29:24 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Agenda]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>To be determined once the meeting ends.<br><br>
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="obsidian://open?vault=Project%20Digitalization&amp;file=attachments%2FPowerPoint%2FKnowledge%20Base%20Migration.pptx" rel="noopener" class="external-link" href="obsidian:\\open?vault=Project Digitalization&amp;file=attachments%2FPowerPoint%2FKnowledge Base Migration.pptx" target="_blank">Knowledge Base Migration PowerPoint Presentation</a>
]]></description><link>meetings\meeting-006-knowledge-base-migration.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Meetings/Meeting 006 - Knowledge Base Migration.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 03:38:27 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Memorandum for Knowledge Base Migration]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>To the Project Digitalization Development Team,<br>I am writing to inform you about an important update regarding our team’s knowledge base.<br>Recently, we encountered an issue with Notion’s billing, where the development team was only supposed to be charged for their Notion AI add-on worth $10 USD. However, the card I have provided did not go through and Notion notified us that if we did not pay for the failed invoice worth around $4 USD, not only are we going to lose the Notion AI add-on but also the Notion Education Plus Plan granted to us, which allowed the development team to upload large images as well as integrate charts and automations in our Notion workspaces (which the accumulated cost will be $22 per user per month). Despite my efforts to resolve this with Notion’s support team, they did not respond to the issue and the charges remain unchanged. As a result, your access to the Project Digitalization Notion workspace has been permanently revoked.<br>To ensure that our work continues smoothly and without further interruptions, we have decided to migrate our knowledge base to Microsoft 365. This transition will provide us with a more stable and cost-effective solution moving forward. The migration period is expected to conclude on October 06, 2024. After the migration period, all members of the Project Digitalization development team will be oriented on how our workflow on Microsoft 365 will work.<br>I understand that this change may cause some inconvenience, and I appreciate your patience and cooperation during this transition period. This is to make sure that we have a reliable and efficient knowledge management system in place.<br>Thank you for your understanding and support.<br><br>Best regards,<br>Marc Victor L. Velasquez<br>
Producer, Project Digitalization<br>
<a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="mailto:velasquez.marcvictor@auf.edu.ph" rel="noopener" class="external-link" href="mailto:velasquez.marcvictor@auf.edu.ph" target="_blank">velasquez.marcvictor@auf.edu.ph</a>]]></description><link>memorandums\memorandum-for-knowledge-base-migration.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Memorandums/Memorandum for Knowledge Base Migration.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 09:13:33 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Agenda]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br><br>]]></description><link>templates\meeting-notes.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Templates/Meeting Notes.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2024 00:26:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Knowledge Base Setup]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>Hello World]]></description><link>knowledge-base-setup.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Knowledge Base Setup.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 09:13:33 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Project Information]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Shattered Eternity (formerly called Project Digitalization) is a hybrid of an action and turn-based role-playing game set in a post-apocalyptic (and somewhat dystopian) world where a phenomenon called the Digitalization gave humanity God-like powers that led to their slow and eventual demise. The player takes control of the main protagonist and two side characters where they will navigate the world in a third-person perspective (similar to The Legend of Heroes: Trails through Daybreak).<br><br>
<br>Adrienne Clark Atim - Director, Level Designer, Developer
<br>Marc Victor Velasquez - Producer, Technical Director, 3D Artist, Environment Designer, Music Director, Music Composer
<br>Ivan David - Story Writer Assistant, Developer
<br>Aris Justine Dizon - Quality Assurance, Level Designer, Developer
]]></description><link>project-information.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Project Information.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 09:13:33 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>